In this clip we'll talk about how to obtain information about phobias for you or a loved one.
One of the things that you want to do is, if you have access to the Internet, hop on the net, it's the fastest way to get the information you might be looking for.
Now if you type in phobia, you're going to get a lot of hits, so you want to try to narrow it down.
Type in the name of a specific phobia in a search engine such as Google, or Ask.com, or Yahoo.com and you'll get a lot more information.
If you want to go to a source that's a little bit more specific and health based, you can go to something like WebMD.com, or Mayo (that's M-a-y-o)Clinic.com, or you can also go to the National Institute of Mental Health web site, where they have, not only what different phobias are, but kind of some of the treatments.
And some of these websites even have questionnaires.
If you think you have a phobia, or you may have a phobia if, and you can kind of check it off.
And then the great thing is you can print this out, take it to your physician and say, "hey, I took this test, and this what it came out, what do you think?", so it can actually be a very good tool.
If you're a family member, same thing applies;
you can still do these things.
Maybe instead of taking it yourself, you can hand it to the person that's having the phobia or the problem.
If you don't have access to the Internet, you can go to your public library, you can look at magazines, again you can talk to doctors, because they'll also have this information that's available.